Guide to the McFarland-Hall-Beck Families Papers, 1772-1928 AIS.1971.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
McFarland-Hall-Beck Families Papers
1772-1928
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Beck family
Hall family
AIS.1971.01
1.88 Linear Feet
The papers of the McFarland-Hall-Beck Families are the records of three families originally settled in Virginia (now West Virginia). This collection includes genealogies, histories, correspondence, memoirs, journals, business and legal papers, photographs and memorabilia. Digital reproductions of the material is available online.
Existence and Location of Copies
Digital reproductions of the collection are available online in the finding aid.
Biography
The McFarland Family traces its descendants from William McFarland, born about 1750 in County Tyrone, Ireland. William's eldest son, James, immigrated to the United States, and William, with part of the family, followed in 1812. William Jr. began manufacturing cotton goods for the Providence Dye House (Providence, Rhode Island), before becoming a U.S. citizen and enrolling as a volunteer in the cadets. William Jr. moved west and settled in Finley Township, Washington, Pa., where he volunteered in the Monroe Standard until honorably discharged. William Jr. went on to hold several county offices over the next few years before moving to Marshall County, Virginia, in 1834. Here he served as Justice of the Peace, sheriff, and school commissioner before his death on March 13, 1866. The McFarland Family (including the parents of William Jr.) are buried in a cemetery on Roberts Ridge, West Virginia.
The Hall Family immigrated to this country from England during the mid-eighteenth century. The family descends from Thomas Hall who was married to Rebecca Story. The Halls raised a family in Delaware and may have lived in Snow Hill, Maryland, at some point. Thomas Hall died May 29, 1772, near Duck Creek Cross Roads, Delaware. The remaining family moved west after the end of the Revolutionary War, settling by the forks of the Cheat River, a few miles below Morgantown, West Virginia. During that time the area was considered a part of Virginia and was heavily forested. Stockades were built to protect settlers from attacks by Indians. As the attacks became less frequent, the Halls and other settlers began moving up the Monongahela River, trading their furs in Pittsburgh.
The Beck Family of Ohio County, West Virginia, are descendants of Lemuel Beck. One of the descendants, Samuel Beck, received a commission as first lieutenant of Company S, First Regional, West Virginia National Guard on November 30, 1898. Samuel Beck was the administrator of the T. B. McFarland Estate.
Scope and Content Notes
The papers of the McFarland-Hall-Beck Families are the records of three families who originally settled in Virginia (now West Virginia). The papers include correspondence, as well as memoirs and accounts of battles, particularly during the Civil War. This collection includes genealogies, histories, correspondence, memoirs, journals, business and legal papers, photographs and memorabilia of the McFarland, Hall, and Beck Families.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Dr. Van Beck Hall of the University of Pittsburgh January 4, 1971, and Mrs. Wayland Mary Bowser, August 7, 1973.
Previous Citation
McFarland-Hall-Beck Families Papers, 1772-1928, AIS.1971.01, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Family papers; Soldiers -- Correspondence; Personal papers; Soldiers -- West Virginia -- Correspondence; Soldiers -- Virginia -- Correspondence; West Virginia -- Social life and customs; Virginia -- Social life and customs; West Virginia -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Virginia -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865.; West Virginia -- Genealogy; Virginia -- Genealogy; Family histories -- West Virginia; Family histories -- Virginia; Hall family; Beck family; McFarland family
- McFarland Family, I.
  - Genealogy and history (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Photographs (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Memorabilia (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - William McFarland's correspondence (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - William McFarland's business papers (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - William McFarland's memoirs and journals (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - William McFarland's Justice of the Peace records (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - William McFarland's school commissioner records (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - William McFarland's legal papers (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - William McFarland's miscellaneous documents (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Thomas B. McFarland's correspondence (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Thomas B. McFarland's Civil War letters (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Thomas B. McFarland's Civil War memoirs (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Thomas B. McFarland's letters (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Thomas B. McFarland's compositions (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Thomas B. McFarland's Civil War memorabilia (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Thomas B. McFarland's memorabilia (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Thomas B. McFarland's business papers (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Sara A. McFarland (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Robert C. McFarland (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - William McFarland Jr. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Mrs. T.B. McFarland's correspondence (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Mrs. T.B. McFarland's memorabilia (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Hall Family, II.
  - Genealogy and history (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Arthur A. Hall (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Byron William Hall (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - George Hall (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Homer C. Hall (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Reynear Milton Hall (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Jordan Hall (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - S.E. Hall (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Thomas Hall (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Van Byron Hall (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Hall Family miscellaneous papers (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Hall Family Association, 1929-1932 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Beck Family, III.
  - Genealogy and history (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Memorabilia, 1899-1928 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Deeds, 1807-1891 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Beck family correspondence, 1823-1833 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Beck family correspondence, 1846-1875 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Beck family correspondence, 1875-1898 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Articles of agreement, 1813-1890 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Tax receipts, 1799-1893 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Insurance policies (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Samuel Beck's agreements (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Samuel Beck's surveys (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Samuel Beck's receipts (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Samuel Beck's wills (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Joel Vickers Beck (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - John Ferval Beck (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Lemuel Beck's correspondence (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Lemuel Beck's agreements (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Lemuel Beck's journals (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Lemuel Beck's receipts (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Lemuel Beck's memoranda books (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Lemuel Beck's documents (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Lemuel Beck's surveys (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Lemuel Beck's report (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Lemuel Beck Jr. letters (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Lemuel Beck Jr. agreements (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Martha Beck (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Sallie Beck (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Samuel J. Beck's correspondence (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Samuel Beck's commission as First Lieutenant (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Samuel Beck poem (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Samuel Beck's invoices (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Samuel Beck's Promissory note (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Samuel Beck's memoranda book (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Samuel Beck's receipts (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Mrs. Samuel Beck's correspondence (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Beck family photographs (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Miscellaneous, IV.
  - Boggs family (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Taylor, Milligan (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Vickers family (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Account books (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Memoranda books (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Seiberts Western Review (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - 1856 Boston Almanac (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Etiquette and the Usages of Scoiety (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Newspapers (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous publications (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Posters and broadsides (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Clippings, 1840 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Indenture, 1818 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Business papers (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Documents (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Related letters and memorabilia (Box 3, Folder 25)